Register of the George Sokolsky Papers, 1916-1962
Hoover Institution Archives
- SUBJECT FILE, 1918-1962.
  - Anti-Semitism. Includes examples of American anti-Semitic literature (Box 240, Folder 1)
  - Argentina (Folder 2)
  - Arnold, Thurman W. (Folder 3)
  - Asia (Folder 4)
  - Australia (Folder 5)
  - Austria (Folder 6)
  - Bernstein, Leonard. Includes photostat of Bernstein's affidavit in support of passport application, 1954 (Folder 7)
  - Bez, Nick (Folder 8)
  - Bialer, Seweryn (Folder 9)
  - British Guiana (Folder 10)
  - Bunche, Ralph (Folder 11)
  - Byrnes, James F. (Folder 12)
  - Canada (Box 241, Folder 1)
  - Central Intelligence Agency. Photostat of report on agency's collaboration with anti-Communist forces in China (Folder 2)
  - Chaplin, Charles (Folder 3)
  - China
    - General
      - Clippings (Folder 4)
      - Reports (Folder 5-7)
    - Government Bureau of Economic Information (Shanghai) (Box 242, Folder 1)
    - Labor movement (Folder 2)
    - Religion
      - Clippings (Folder 3)
      - Reports (Folder 4)
    - Treaties. Includes reports and articles on the issue of extraterritoriality (Folder 5)
    - United States. Includes articles by Stanley Hornbeck on Sino-American relations (Folder 6)
  - Communism (Box 243)
    - South America (Folder 1)
    - United States. Includes reports and dossiers prepared by J. B. Matthews on the supposed political affiliations of various groups and individuals (Folder 2-4)
    - United States (Box 244, Folder 1-3)
    - United States (Box 245, Folder 1)
  - Condon, Edward U. (Folder 2)
  - Coordinating Committee for Democratic Action (Folder 3)
  - Copland, Aaron (Folder 4)
  - Counterattack (Folder 5)
  - Creigh, Thomas (Folder 6)
  - Crouch, Paul (Folder 7)
  - Cuba (Folder 8)
  - Davies, John P. (Folder 9)
  - Dean, Vera Micheles (Folder 10)
  - Delaney, Edward (Folder 11)
  - Democratic Party (U.S.) (Folder 12)
  - Digest of Current Communist Activities (Folder 13)
  - Dillon, Douglas (Folder 14)
  - Eaton, Cyrus, Mr. and Mrs. (Box 246, Folder 1)
  - Education - United States (Folder 2-4)
  - Education - United States (Contd.) (Box 247, Folder 1-2)
  - Einstein, Albert (Folder 3)
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Box 248, Folder 1)
  - Electronics Corporation of America (Folder 2)
  - Emerson, Thomas (Folder 3)
  - Europe (Folder 4)
  - Faubus, Orval (Folder 5)
  - Federal Communications Commission (Folder 6)
  - Flynn, Edward J. (Folder 7)
  - Food for Freedom (Folder 8)
  - Forrestal, James (Folder 9)
  - Foundations (Box 249, Folder 1)
  - Ford Foundation (Folder 2)
  - France (Folder 3)
  - Frankfurter, Felix (Folder 4)
  - Franklin, Mitchell (Folder 5)
  - Freedom Agenda (Folder 6)
  - Fund for the Republic (Folder 7)
  - Gellhorn, Walter (Box 250, Folder 1)
  - General Airline and Film Corp. (Folder 2)
  - General Motors (Folder 3-5)
  - Germany (Box 251, Folder 1)
  - Great Britain (Folder 2-4)
  - Green, William (Folder 5)
  - Gunther, John (Folder 6)
  - Harrington, Michael (Box 252, Folder 1)
  - Health - United States (Folder 2-4)
  - Hersey, John (Folder 5)
  - Hiss, Alger (Folder 6)
  - Hooker, West (Box 253, Folder 1)
  - Hoover, Herbert C. Includes report (in folder 2) by George Bronson Rea on Hoover's activities in China (Folder 2-4)
  - Hoover, J. Edgar (Folder 5)
  - Hoover Commission (Folder 6)
  - Hu, Shih (Box 254)
    - Clippings (Folder 1)
    - Writings. Includes autobiographical material and essays on political philosophy. In English and Chinese (Folder 2-4)
  - Hungary (Folder 5)
  - India (Box 255, Folder 1)
  - Indonesia (Folder 2)
  - Institute of Pacific Relations (Folder 3-4)
  - International Latex Corporation (Folder 5)
  - Israel (Folder 6)
  - Ithaca Reading Room Against Communism (Folder 7)
  - Japan (Box 256, Folder 1)
  - Javits, Jacob K. (Folder 2)
  - Jessup, Philip K. (Folder 3)
  - John Birch Society (Folder 4)
  - Jowitt, William Allen, Lord (Folder 5)
  - Judaism (Folder 6)
  - Katz, Sidney (Folder 7)
  - Kennan, George (Folder 8)
  - Klein, Julius (Folder 9)
  - Kohlberg, Alfred. Includes material relating to the Alfred Kohlberg Memorial Fund (Folder 10-11)
  - Korea (Box 257, Folder 1)
  - Krivitsky, Walter (Folder 2)
  - Labor unions - United States (Folder 3-5)
  - La Follette Civil Liberties Commission (Folder 6)
  - Lamont, Corliss (Folder 7)
  - Latin America (Folder 8)
  - Lattimore, Owen (Folder 9)
  - League of Nations. Includes League reports on China (Box 258, Folder 1)
  - Lebanon (Folder 2)
  - Lincoln, E. E. (Folder 3)
  - The Listener (Folder 4)
  - Loeb, Dorothy (Folder 5)
  - Lubin, Isidor (Folder 6)
  - MacArthur, Douglas (Folder 7)
  - McCarthy, Joseph (Folder 8)
  - Mazour, Anatole (Folder 9)
  - Merchant Marine - United States (Folder 10)
  - Metcalfe, John C. (Box 259, Folder 1)
  - Middle East (Folder 2)
  - Milk industry (Folder 3)
  - Morris, Robert. Includes autobiographical manuscript by Morris (incomplete) (Folder 4)
  - Morse, Wayne (Folder 5)
  - Motion picture industry
    - Clippings
      - General (Folder 6-7)
      - House Un-American Activities Committee (Folder 8-9)
    - Correspondence (Box 260)
      - General (Folder 1-3)
      - Columbia Pictures (Folder 4-5)
      - Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer (Box 261, Folder 1-2)
      - Paramount (Folder 3)
      - Twentieth Century-Fox (Folder 4)
    - Dossiers. Includes lists compiled by investigators showing supposed political affiliations of individuals active in motion picture industry (Box 262, Folder 1-2)
    - Memos and notes (Folder 3)
    - Newsletters and press releases (Folder 4)
    - Testimony. Includes transcripts of hearings before the House Un-American Activities Committee (Folder 5)
  - Murrow, Edward R. (Folder 6)
  - National Republic Lettergram (Box 263, Folder 1)
  - National Union of Students (Folder 2)
  - Nehru, Jawaharlal (Folder 3)
  - Nelson, Steve (Folder 4)
  - Newsprint industry (Folder 5)
  - Nixon, Richard (Folder 6)
  - Norman, Edgerton Herbert (Folder 7)
  - Oppenheimer, J. Robert (Folder 8)
  - Paar, Jack (Folder 9)
  - Pacifica Foundation (Folder 10)
  - Panuch, J. Anthony (Folder 11)
  - Pauling, Linus (Folder 12)
  - Peace Corps (Box 264, Folder 1)
  - Pearson, Drew (Folder 2)
  - Pepper, Claude (Folder 3)
  - Pharmaceutical industry (Folder 4)
  - Poland (Folder 5)
  - Radio industry (Folder 6-8)
  - Railroads (Box 265, Folder 1)
  - Religion - United States (Folder 2-4)
  - Remington, William Walter (Box 266, Folder 1)
  - Republican Party (U.S.) (Folder 2)
  - Reuther, Walter (Folder 3)
  - Rockefeller Foundation (Folder 4)
  - Roosevelt, Elliot (Folder 5)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Folder 6)
  - Rubin, Jay (Folder 7)
  - Schwarz, Fred (Folder 8)
  - Searchlight on PAC (Folder 9)
  - Seldes, George (Folder 10)
  - Shigemitsu, Mamoru (Folder 11)
  - Silver Shirts (Folder 12)
  - Smith, Gerald L. K. (Folder 13)
  - Sobell, Morton (Box 267, Folder 1)
  - Soong, T. V. Includes material, in English and Chinese, concerning the financial policies of the Nationalist government in China (Folder 2)
  - Soong family. Includes biographical material concerning C. J. Soong (Folder 3)
  - Soviet Union (Folder 4)
  - Stanford University (Folder 5)
  - Stassen, Harold (Folder 6)
  - Studebaker-Packard Corp. (Folder 7)
  - Sun, Yat-Sen (Folder 8)
  - Taft, Robert A. Includes material relating to the Taft Memorial Fund and the Robert A. Taft Institute of Government (Box 268, Folder 1-2)
  - Taiwan (Folder 3)
  - Television (Folder 4)
  - Taylor, Telford (Folder 5)
  - Theater (Folder 6)
  - Thomas, Elbert (Folder 7)
  - Time (Folder 8)
  - Truman, Harry S. (Folder 9)
  - The Truth About Communism (Folder 10)
  - United Nations (Folder 11)
  - United Parents Association (Box 269, Folder 1)
  - United States - Armed Forces (Folder 2-3)
  - United States - Economic conditions (Folder 4-5)
  - United States - Economic conditions (Contd.) (Box 270, Folder 1-4)
  - United States - Economic conditions (Contd.) (Box 271, Folder 1-4)
  - United States - Economic conditions (Contd.) (Box 272, Folder 1-4)
  - United States - Economic conditions (Contd.) (Box 273, Folder 1-2)
  - United States - Foreign relations (Folder 3-4)
  - United States - Politics and government (Box 274, Folder 1-4)
  - United States - Politics and government (Contd.) (Box 275, Folder 1-4)
  - United States - Politics and government (Contd.) (Box 276, Folder 1-4)
  - United States - Politics and government (Contd.) (Box 277, Folder 1-4)
  - United States - Politics and government (Contd.) (Box 278, Folder 1-2)
  - United States. Congress. Senate. Committee on the Judiciary. Subcommittee to Investigate the Administration of the Internal Security Act (McCarran Committee (Folder 2-4)
  - United States. Congress. Senate. Committee to Investigate the Munitions Industry (Nye Committee) (Box 279, Folder 1)
  - United States. Department of State (Folder 2)
  - Universities and colleges - Middle East (Folder 3)
  - Venezuela (Folder 4)
  - Veterans - United States (Folder 5)
  - Walker, Edwin A. (Box 280, Folder 1)
  - Welles, Orson (Folder 2)
  - Western Tax Council (Folder 3)
  - White, Harry Dexter (Folder 4)
  - Willkie, Wendell (Folder 5)
  - Wirt, William (Folder 6)
  - World War, 1939-1945 (Folder 7)
  - Yankwich, Leon R. (Folder 8)
- PRINTED MATTER, 1919-1962
  - Clippings, 1919-1962. Contemporary newspaper articles, arranged by Sokolsky according to topic, in original envelopes. Includes printed copies of some articles written by Sokolsky in China, as well as copies of his syndicated column, "These Days" (Box 281-385.)
  - Publications received, 1922-1962. Books, brochures, newsletters, and pamphlets. Includes one box (386) of material in Chinese (Box 386-389.)
- OVERSIZE MATERIAL, 1919-1962. (Box Box No. 390-391.)
  Brochures, charts, maps, and printed material, in English and Chinese. Includes a linen table cloth, made in the Soviet Union, relating to Sokolsky's article for King Features of 1950 May 4
- AUDIOVISUAL FILE, 1917-1962
  - Sound Recordings (Box 392)
    - Flexidisc containing speech by Joseph R. McCarthy on the Harry Dexter White case, 1953 November 24
    - Flexidisc containing recording of Robert A. Taft, 1950 April 7
  - Sound recording of speech on food aid plan to Belgium and other Nazi-occupied countries, undated
    Conditions Governing Access note
    Use copy reference number: 59004_a_0001717
    Sokolsky details the plan to send food aid to countries occupied by Nazi Germany and how to pay for it. An experimental program, it is not meant to encompass all people in the countries, nor is it meant as aid to Nazi Germany. Foods are nutrient-rich items, such as fats and vegetables. It only applies three million people served at supervised soup-kitchens; two million children and one million expectant mothers and elderly. A person in Belgium is down to 960 calories a day. An ordinary American needs a minimum of 2000 calories a day; a heavy worker needs 4000. The aid will be paid for by the treasuries of the recipient countries. Presented by the National Committee on Food for the Small Democracies
  - Sound recording of speech at the Lion's Club and Candid Camera from meeting of TWIG #70, 1941 March 12-18
    Use copy reference number: 59004_a_0001718
    Side A: speech at the Lion's Club, 18 Mar 1941. Sokolsky details the plan to send food aid to countries occupied by Nazi Germany and how to pay for it. An experimental program. It only applies three million people served at committee-supervised soup-kitchens; two million children and one million expectant mothers and elderly. Belgium is first because its citizenry is down to 960 calories a day; the minimum for the average American is 2000.
    Side B: Candid Camera from Meeting of TWIG #70, Artist: William Corley, 12 Mar 1941. Reporting on a women's club knitting a quilt to benefit a children's hospital.
  - Photographs
    - 2 prints of publicity photos of George E. Sokolsky, n.d. (Folder A)
    - 1 print of Lola Kinel, 1920 (Folder B)
    - 14 prints depicting scenes in Beijing, including two of a student demonstration, 1917-1918 (Folder C)
    - 21 prints showing the construction of the Sino-American highway by the U.S. Marine Corps 5th Engineers, 3rd Brigade, China, 1928 (Folder D)
    - 39 prints relating to the Battle of Woosung, China, n.d. (Folder E)
    - 1 print showing Douglas MacArthur with Charles A. Willoughby, n.d. (Folder F)
    - 1 newsphoto depicting Dwight D. Eisenhower with Viscount Montgomery and George Zhukov, 1945 June 16 (Folder G)
    - 2 prints showing Marshal Tito (Josip Broz) and the American ambassador to Yugoslavia, Richard C. Patterson, Jr., n.d. (Folder H)
    - 1 print depicting Richard M. Nixon and family, 1952 (Folder I)